以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
我决定告诉你一件事
I'm determined to tell you something
关于我刚刚得到的卷积规则
about the convolution rule I just get
靠近它，但我还没有
close to it but I haven't quite got
在那里，实际上我想说
there and actually I'd like to say
东西也为什么卷积
something also about why convolution is
所以重要的这一点，我在这里提到过的
so important this I mentioned here a
关于深度学习中图像的论文
paper about images in deep learning by
它有三位作者，这两位是作者
it has three authors and these are two
他们也许你认识Hinton的
of them maybe you recognize Hinton's
说他原来是英国人
name he's originally English he was in
在圣地亚哥了好几年
in San Diego for quite a few years and
现在他在加拿大，所以多伦多和
now he's in Canada so Toronto and
蒙特利尔现在是很重要的中心
Montreal are big centers now for deep
学习儿子他是他真的其中之一
learning son he's he's really one of the
领导者之一，所以是队长
one of the leaders and and so is skipper
所以也许你知道，那种
so maybe you know that the sort of
深度学习的进步往往是
progress of deep learning can often be
在这些比赛所测量
measured in these competitions that are
你知道每年举办一次
held like about every year for you know
怎么做得有多好
how how well how well does something
人们设计并执行一个完整的神经
people design and execute a whole neural
网和这是一场比赛
net and this was a competition about
图像，以便真的苛刻
images so that is really demanding
因为正如我上次说的那样
because as I said last time an image has
如此多的样本像素那么多
so many samples so many pixels that the
计算问题是巨大的
computational problem is enormous and
那是你什么时候去的
that's when you would go to
卷积神经网络CNN因为a
convolutional neural nets CNN because a
卷积网占用较少的权重
convolutional net takes fewer weights
因为同样的重量正在出现
because the same weight is appearing
沿着对角线
along diagonals
它不需要
it doesn't need a
完整的权重矩阵只有一个顶行
full matrix of weights just one top row
权重反正所以这是一个
of weights anyway so this is one of the
历史文献中的
historical papers in the in the in the
深度学习的历史我会读
history of deep learning I'll just read
我们训练了几句这样的句子
a couple of sentences we trained so this
是我们训练深刻的抽象概念
is the abstract we trained a deep a
大型深度卷积神经网络
large deep convolutional neural network
但我只是说他们说了
but I'll just enter say that they took
它跑了五天两个GPU，因此
it ran for five days on two GPUs so it
我们会看到这是一个巨大的问题
was an enormous problem as we'll see so
我们训练了一个大型深编织网CNN
we trained a large deep knit network CNN
分类120万高分辨率图像
to classify 1.2 million high-res images
在图像网，所以图像网是一个来源
in image net so image net is a source of
数以百万计的图像和测试数据
millions of images and on the test data
他们我们最后的句子可能是一个
they well we the last sentences may be a
关键我们输入了这个模型的变体
key we entered a variant of this model
在2012年的比赛中
in the competition 2012 competition and
我们取得了前5名的测试错误
we achieved a winning top 5 test error
比率为15％，相比之下为26％
rate of 15% compared to 26% for for the
排名第二的球队，他们得到了15％的失误
second-place team so 15% error they got
其余26％是最好的
26% was the best that the rest of the
世界的确如此以及当他和他的时候
world did and so so that and and when he
显示网络，你意识到了什么
shows the network you realized what's
什么进入它它有卷积
what's gone into it it has convolution
图层和它有一些正常的图层和
layers and it has some normal layers and
它有最大的池层来切割
it has max pooling layers to cut the
尺寸向下一点点，它是和
dimension down a little bit and it's and
一半的样本放在一个GPU上
and half the samples go on one GPU and
另一半和某些点
half another and at certain points
两个GPU之间的层互连
layers interconnect between the two GPUs
所以减少过度拟合你
and so to reduce overfitting you
记住，关键问题是
remember that's the key problem is to
完全减少过度拟合
reduce overfitting in this in the fully
连接层那些是普通的
connected layers those are the ordinary
层与
layers with
我们使用的全重量矩阵
full weight matrices we employed a
最近开发的正规化称为
recently developed regularization called
辍学所以作为一种工具辍学如果
drop out so drop out as a tool which if
你觉得你在这个世界上
you're in this world you you I think
通过看到这一点，Hinton再次提出了这一点
Hinton proposed it again by seeing that
它的工作原理只是小心一点
it worked it's just a careful it's a
小心摒弃一些数据
careful drop out of of some of the data
它减少了数据量和它
it reduces the amount of data and it
这样做不会伤害问题
doesn't harm the the problem so so the
神经网络有6000万个参数
neural network has 60 million parameters
6000万神经元65万
60 million with 650 thousand neurons
五个卷积层和三个
five convolutional layers and three
我刚提到的完全连接的层
fully connected layers I just mentioned
这可以，如果你只是谷歌
this and you could if you just google
这两个名字你会在网上
these two names you would on the web
查看该文件提出将拿出
view that paper this paper would come up
但它就是这样我们正在谈论的
but it's so it's we're talking about the
真实的东西在这里卷积是一回事
real thing here convolution is something
每个人都想了解我，我会
everybody wants to understand and I I'd
自从我开始好几天以来
like to since I've started several days
以前，我想记住什么
ago and I'd like to remember what
卷积意味着如果我，就让我这样
convolution means let me so if I
卷入两个向量，我寻找
convolve two vectors and I look for the
案例组成部分答案了
case component of the answer the the
计算公式为我添加备份C的所有时间DS
formula is I add up all the C's times DS
其中i+J指标增加至k为什么
where the index i + j adds to k why do
你做了这样的事情
you do such a thing
因为c可能用a表示
because c might be represented by a
多项式说x++c+X到第n个
polynomial say x + + c + X to the nth
和D可能由另一个人代表
and D might be represented by another
一个D1X加MX到M让我们
one D 1 X plus the M X to the M let's
说
say
当我乘以时，就会产生卷积
and convolution arises when I multiply
那些多项式因为一个典型的
those polynomials because for a typical
然后收集条款，因为一个典型的
and then collect terms because a typical
X的力量对X说X
power of X say X to the K the
系数很好我们如何得到X.
coefficients are well how do we get X to
K乘以这些乘以C
the K in multiplying these I multiply C
在这里的某个地方没有时间DK
naught times a DK somewhere in here
对于K来说，这将是一个DKX，所以没有
would be a DK X to the K so a C naught
时间DK会给我一个X到K.
times a DK would give me an X to the K
每个人看到这个术语和c1次
term and a c1 times everybody sees this
现在来了，c1已经有了X
coming now c1 has an X in it already so
我们会在那里看DK减去1
over there we would look at DK minus 1
少了一个X所以它将是c1DK
with one less X so it would be c1 DK
减1，这只是你做了什么时
minus 1 this is just what you do when
你乘以多项式和点
you multiply polynomials and the point
是我们认识这些术语的方式
is that the way we recognize those terms
是指数0和K的指数
is that the exponents 0 and K the
指数1和K减1总是加
exponents 1 and K minus 1 always add to
K这就是这个公式的来源
K so that's where this formula comes
从我们采取C次D隐藏在后面
from we take a C times a D hiding behind
或者一个CX到I和一个DJX到J
or a C X to the I and a DJ X to the J
当加I加J为K时，这是X.
and when a plus I plus J is K this is X
对K而言，这就是我们的用语
to the K and that's the term we're
捕获所以这是系数
capturing so this is the coefficient of
那个词，让我写一个
that term and let me write it in a
你的方式略有不同
slightly different way where you
实际上看得更清楚了
actually see even more clearly
卷积运算所以J是K减去I
convolution operating so J is K minus I
对，所以它是CIDJ的总和但是
right so it's the sum of C I D J but the
j具有被K减去我所以这是
J has to be K minus I so this is the
这是记住公式的方法
this is the way to remember the formula
为
for the
内容中的系数CstarDin
coefficients in the content C star D in
你看看C的时间DS的卷积
the convolution you look at C's times DS
这是它的一种乘法形式
it's it's a form of multiplication it
来自普通乘法
comes from ordinary multiplication of
多项式以及收集术语时
polynomials and when you collect terms
你正在收集看IC和K.
you're collecting see the I C and the K
减去身份证，你可以尽一切可能
minus I D and you're taking all possible
眼睛所以它只是总结所有可能的
eyes so it's just sum over all possible
那里的眼睛给你的案例答案
eyes there to give you the case answer
好吧，看看你是否有这个想法
well just to see if you got the idea
什么是两个卷积
what would be the convolution of two
函数假设我有一个函数f
functions suppose I have a function f of
X和我想传达G的功能
X and I want to convey the function G of
X没关系，注意到我没有
X okay and notice that I have not
盘旋这个符号所以我没有做
circled this symbol so I'm not doing
周期性卷积我只是在做
periodic convolution I'm just doing
直截了当的卷积所以是什么
straightforward convolution so what are
我们将在两个案例的情况下
we going to have in the case of two
功能是什么意思
functions what would that mean a
函数的卷积我是我的
convolution of functions I'm I'm in
在这里平行，两个卷积
parallel here with a convolution of two
矢量这么认为的，这些现在有
vectors so think of these now have
成为案例组件的功能
become functions the case component has
真的，我应该在X上说F星G
become really I should say F star G at X
这真的是平行的
that's really that's really the parallel
对此，让我这样，我告诉你
to this so let me so I'm I'm telling you
我在X告诉你的答案
the answer at X here I told you the
在K案例中回答案例组成部分
answer at K case the case component
看起来像x值是什么
looks like that what does the x value of
卷积看起来像函数
the convolution look like for functions
好吧，我只是要这样做，我要去
okay I'm just going to do this I'm gonna
做同样的事情，而不是总结
do the same as this instead of summing
我将做什么整合而不是C
what will I do integrate instead of C
我将获得X的f
sub I I'll have f of X
眼睛指数我正在改变
eyes the index I is changing over to the
连续变量X和现在G代替
continuous variable X and now G instead
DK减去我这里有什么呢？
of DK minus I what do I have here so so
它是K减去I分量
it's uh it's K minus I component that
会去让我把它写下来ŧ
will go to let me just write it down t
减去X所以在这个翻译中F是
minus X so so in this translation F is
被翻译成C或对不起F是
being translated to C or sorry F is
对应CG对应DK
corresponds to C G corresponds to D K
对应X而且对不起我
corresponds to X and oh sorry I
对应于X和J，K对应于I.
corresponds to X and J and K minus I
对应于t减X所以K
corresponds to t minus X so so K
对应于T，这是什么
corresponds to T that's this is what
将是两个人的卷积
would be the convolution of two
功能哦它是T坏的功能
functions oh it's a function of T bad
T的坏符号就是这样
bad notation to the T is sort of this
转移量
the amount of shift
你看我已经转移了G我已经逆转了它
you see I've shifted G I've reversed it
并且翻转它和通过移位它
and flipped it and shifting it by
不同的金额这就是你的意思
different amounts T it's it's what you
在过滤器中它只是一直都是
have in a filter it's just all of always
因此在信号处理中存在
present in in in signal processing so
这将是一个定义，或者我可以
that would be a definition or I could if
你喜欢我，如果你想要一个X变量
you like I if you want an X variable to
出来让我做一个X变量来
come out let me make an X variable come
通过交换T和X这样就可以了
out by exchanging T and X so so this
将是X减去TDT我喜欢这样
would be X minus T DT I like that
实际上好一点，就是这样
actually a little better and it's the
积分超过t无穷大到
integral over t minus infinity to
无穷大，如果我们的功能在
infinity if our functions were on the
整条线将会有一个
whole line so that will there will be a
卷积规则
convolution rule for
这将连接到
the that this will connect to the
两个函数的傅里叶变换
Fourier transform of the two functions
在这里，我把它连接到
over here I'm connecting it to the
离散傅里叶变换的两个
discrete Fourier transform of the two
功能，我一直在做
functions and I've been making the
卷积循环所以我可以做什么
convolution cyclic so what does can I
现在添加循环这是普通的
add cyclic now this is ordinary
卷积这就是你所拥有的
convolution this is what you had in the
第一个实验，我认为从拉贾饶
first lab I think from from Raja Rao the
第一个实验中，你还记得你有图
first lab you remember you had to figure
了解了多少组件
out what the how many components the
卷积会有，你没有
convolution would have and you didn't
使它循环，所以循环卷积
make it cyclic so a cyclic convolution
如果这有n个组件而且这有
if if this has n components and this has
n个分量然后卷积有n
n components then the convolution has n
组件，因为你保持是和
components because you keeping yeah and
这是关键数字的长度
it's the key number there the length of
如果F，这个时期和此类似
the period and similarly over here if F
是2pi周期性的，G是2pi周期性的
is 2 pi periodic and G is 2 pi periodic
然后我们可能想要定期做
then we might want to do a periodic
卷积并带来它
convolution and bring it
得到一个也有2pi的答案
get a get an answer that also has 2 pi
期间2pi是的，所以你可以计算
of period 2 pi yeah so you could compute
正弦X与cosx的卷积
the convolution of sine X with cos x for
例
example
好吧，让我们坚持使用矢量，那么它是什么
ok let's stick with vectors so so what's
当我做的时候我让这笔交易
the deal when I make when I make it
当我使它循环然后进入时循环
cyclic when I make it cyclic then in
这个乘法
this multiplication
我真的应该使用我已经介绍过W作为
I really should use I've introduced W as
这不是环外X成为该
that instead of exocyclic X becomes this
这个数字W是2pi结束
this number W which is either 2 pi over
n并且具有属性然后W到
n and has the property then that W to
N是1所以所有的向量
the N is 1 so that all vectors of
大于n可以折叠使用
greater than n can be folded back using
这个规则是长度为n的向量所以我们
this rule to a vector of length n so we
得到一个循环工作，那怎么办
get a cyclic job so how does how does
这改变了我唯一想要的答案
that change the answer well I only want
ķ从0到n减1的
K going from 0 to n minus 1 in the
循环案例我不想要无限多
cyclic case I don't want infinitely many
组件我必须把它们带回来
components I've got to bring them back
再次，让我只说了这些规则
again and let me just say what the rule
你会问我说加J吧
would be you just ask say I plus J you
会看那个模数，那是什么
would look at that modulo n that's what
一个数论者会称之为我们
a number theory person would call it we
我们只看剩余的时间
only look at the remainder when we
用n所以我们所以现在的款项去鸿沟
divide by n so we so now the the sums go
只有从0到n减去1我才得到
only from 0 to n minus 1 and I only get
我从0到n减去1的答案
an answer from 0 to n minus 1 well I've
很快完成了
done that pretty quickly
如果我想这样做就好了
that's if I wanted to do justice to so
是非之间的区别
is the the difference between non
定期
periodic
所以非周期性和周期性的
so non-periodic and periodic will be the
之间的区别所以我有一些数字
difference between so I have some number
对角线t1t2t减零
T zero on the diagonals t 1 t 2 t minus
1t减2等等不断诊断
1 t minus 2 and so on constant diagnosis
关键名称有三胞胎和if
the key name there is triplets and if
这是周期性的，然后我会说CCC
it's periodic then I have I'll say C CC
然后下一个我们看到一个C一个
and then the next one we see one C one
来到C1和C2即将到来
coming around to C 1 and C 2 coming
所以它就像n期n那样
around so it's so as n by n period n so
这是一个循环矩阵nnok
it's a it's a circulant matrix n by n ok
这只是这是大局，我
that's just that's the big picture and I
想想你正在做的第一个实验室
think in that first lab you were doing
你的休息做非循环的情况
your rest to do the non circulant case
因为这是你必须在一个
because that's the one where you have to
做一点耐心会是什么
do a little patience what will be the
长度是什么长度
length yeah what would be the length of
非循环的
a non-circular
所以现在假设C假设没有循环
so not circulant now suppose C suppose
C矢量具有P分量和D
the C vector has P components and the D
矢量有Q组件有多少
vector has Q components how many
在那里卷积组件，所以我
components in there convolution so I
把那个问题写下来因为我
write that question down cuz I that
带来了差异在这里是的
brings out the difference here yeah so
所以如果我有P，如果C有C有P.
so if I have P if C has C has P
组件
components
他有线索组件则
he has cue components then the
C和D的卷积有多少
convolution of C and D has how many so
我正在成倍增长，所以这真的是这样
I'm multiplying so it's really this
对应于P次多项式
corresponds to a polynomial of degree P
减去1次P次的右多项式
minus 1 right polynomials of degree P
减1，这家伙将是Q学位
minus 1 and this guy would be degree Q
减1度Q减1和我
minus 1 degree Q minus 1 and what I
将它们与广告的程度相乘
multiply them what's the degree just ad
又有多少系数以及一个更
and how many coefficients well one more
我必须记住这个愚蠢的零
I have to remember for that stupid zero
订单期限，所以这将有P加Q
order term so this would have P plus Q
减去1个组件，这样就可以了
minus 1 component so that would have
是你不知何故必须的数字
been the number that you somehow had to
在第一个实验室中工作，以便如果
work out in in that first lab so that if
这有最终组件，这有n
this had end components and this had n
这将是n减1只是
this would have to n minus 1 it's just
你必须像你说3加
what you would have like you say 3 plus
在这种情况下，X乘1加2x，P是2Q.
X times 1 plus 2x in this case P is 2 Q
是22组件2组件，如果我
is 2 2 components 2 components and if I
乘以我得到的3X+6X是7x++
multiply those I get 3 X + 6 X is 7x + +
2x平方，所以我有2加2减
2 x squared and so I have 2 plus 2 minus
1等于3个分量X常数X和x
1 equals 3 components X constant X and x
平方是的，明确的仪式
squared yeah clear-rite
是的，这不是我的意思
yep so that's not the that's what I
如果我乘以这些矩阵就会得到
would get if I multiply these matrices
如果我有一个两个对角矩阵三胞胎
if I had a two diagonal matrix Triplets
矩阵乘以两条对角三胞胎
matrix times a two diagonal Triplets
矩阵，会给我一个三
matrix that would give me a three
对角线答案，但如果我这样做
diagonal answer but if I am doing it
定期我只需要
periodically I would only have to
如果那个2x平方将会回来
that that 2x squared would come back if
如果我回来2，所以我只有5
if I come back as a 2 so I just have 5
加上7x好的好的好的好
plus 7x good right good good good
好的，这是对什么的提醒
ok so that's a reminder of what
卷积是循环的非性类似的
convolution is cyclic a non-sex like
矢量和功能好吧，我可以
vectors and functions okay then I can
值和特征向量或下一个
values and eigen vectors or the next
步骤然后卷积规则是
step and then the convolution rule is
最后一步所以特征向量本征
the last step so eigen vectors eigen
当然我可以的圆圈矢量
vectors of the circle of course I can
只做方阵，所以我做
only do square matrices so I'm doing the
周期性情况所以特征向量是
periodic case so the eigen vectors are
特征向量的列
the columns of the of the eigenvector
矩阵，我会称之为
matrix and I'm gonna call it f for
傅立叶因此f是第一个特征向量
Fourier so f is the first eigen vector
是所有那些的X特征向量是
is all ones an X eigen vector is the
第四个根然后是平方根
fourth root of one then the square root
一个我6我吃了第四个我第六个
of one i 6 i ate i fourth i sixth and
最后一个我立刻我6i9好吧那是f
finally one i cubed i 6i9 okay that's f
那些的四个特征向量
those are the four eigen vectors of the
排列P和P中的任何多项式
permutation P and of any polynomial in P
所以我的循环是一些没有我的
so my circulant is is some C naught I
加上C1P加上C​​2P平方+c3pq
plus C 1 P plus C 2 P squared + c 3p q
好吧，最后这就像是一步
okay and finally this is like the step
我们已经准备好了，但没有
we've been almost ready to do but didn't
完全做什么是特征向量
quite do what are the eigen vectors what
呃它的特征向量是什么
uh what eigenvectors are its
特征向量
eigenvectors
那些是p和p的特征向量
so those are the eigenvectors of p and
现在我们只有豌豆的组合
now we have just a combination of peas
所以我认为我的特征向量
so I think the eigenvectors I just
乘我采取相同的组合
multiply I take that same combination of
特征向量是的，是的
the of the eigen vectors yep yep is that
看起来很对不起
that look right so sorry
我很抱歉它们的特征向量
it's I'm sorry its eigenvectors they're
F的列是我的意思
the columns of F the question I meant to
问是它的特征值是什么
ask is what are its eigenvalues that's
关键问题是什么
the key question what are the what are
特征值，我想如果我
the eigenvalues and I think that if I
只需乘以F倍CI即可
just multiply F times C I get the
矩阵C的特征值就是
eigenvalues of the matrix C that's the
美女，如果我的话，这是一个很好的公式
beauty that's the nice formula if my
矩阵只是P，然后这是01
matrix is just P alone then this is 0 1
00我得到1平方我立方但是
0 0 and I get 1 I I squared I cubed but
如果C是其他的一些组合
if C is some other combination of the
豌豆和我采取相同的组合
peas and I take the same combination of
要看的本征向量是的
the eigen vectors to to see yeah
你看到了吗，所以我声称我会
do you see it so I'm claiming that I'll
从中得到C的本征值
get for eigen values of C from this
当然，如果C知道是否
multiplication so of course if C know if
那里只有C然后我才得到C.
there's only C not then I only get C
没有CnaughtCnaughtC没有我得到
naught C naught C naught C naught I get
这是重复四次但是如果
it's a repeat four times repeated but if
如果它是这个组合那么它就是一个
it's a if it's this combination then
矩阵乘法需要
that matrix multiplication takes the
同样的组合是一个
same combination of this is a
的组合
combination of
特征向量和那给了我们
the eigenvectors and and that gives us
给它给我们正确的事情好吧
give it gives us the right thing okay so
这就是现在我只是有一个步骤
that's now I just have one more step for
这是卷积规则然后我
this the convolution rule and then I'm
真的很高兴卷积规则是
happy really the convolution rule is
说明我们在说什么关系
stating what we it's stating a relation
在我们看到的乘法之间
between multiplication which we saw here
和我们解决卷积
and the convolution which we solve for
系数因此是卷积规则
the coefficients so the convolution rule
是乘法和。之间的联系
is a connection between multiplying and
卷积所以让我说什么
convolution and so let me say what that
卷积规则是让我写的
convolution rule is and let me write it
正确如此，所以我采取循环
correctly so so here I take cyclic
卷积我正在处理广场
convolution I'm dealing with square
矩阵一切都是循环这里
matrices everything is cyclic here and
如果我乘以F，我会得到什么呢？
then I get if I multiply by F what do I
现在有
have now
这代表了什么是C和
what does that represent this was C and
B和艾克参与其中，所以我得到了另一个
B and Ike involved them so I got another
循环矩阵所以在这里如此
circulant matrix so so so up here the
矩阵的乘法是C次
multiplication of of matrices is C times
D我想连接那些乘法
D I want to connect multiplying those
汇总了我想要的C语言
matrices with convolving the C's I want
连接使这种连接正确
to connect make that connection right so
这种联系就是卷积
and that connection is the convolution
规则好，所以这将是
rule okay so this would be the
CD的特征值
eigenvalues of CD
让我们暂停，为什么我为什么
let's just pause there why why am I
看着CD的特征值因为
looking at the eigenvalues of CD because
如果我做那个乘法我得到
if I do that multiplication I get
另一个无尖点矩阵C乘以D和
another tipless matrix C times D and the
花粉只有它们的系数
pollen only their coefficients
与C乘以D的对角线相关联
associated on the diagonals of C times D
是卷积的系数
are the coefficients of the convolution
所以对角线的对角线来了
so the its diagonals its diagonals come
从D卷入C6-好吧，现在我
from convolving C with D 6 - okay now I
想在a中找到那些相同的特征值
want to find those same eigenvalues in a
第二种方式和匹配方程式
second way and match and the equation
将是如何卷积规则
will be the convolution rule so how
我能否很好地找到CD的特征值
could I find the eigenvalues of C D well
令人惊讶的是，它们是C的特征值
amazingly they are the eigenvalues of C
D倍的特征值
times the eigenvalues of D I'm gonna
你可以在2比2的基础上测试这条规则
test this rule on two-by-two so you'll
看到一切都在发生，但事实如此
see everything happening but so this is
这是我想要的事实
the main this is the fact that I want to
使用因为是因为C和D通勤
use because yeah because C and D commute
C和D通勤它们具有相同的特征
C and D commute they have the same eigen
矢量，然后是特征值
vectors and then the eigen values just
乘以我可以乘以我可以得到
multiply so I can multiply I can get
以第二种方式取本征
that in a second way by taking the eigen
C的值并乘以
values of C and multiplying those by the
D和I的本征值相乘
eigen values of D and I multiply
按组件分组我乘以
component by component I multiply the
对于本征值的浑身
eigen value for the for the all one's
矢量由所有的特征值
vector by the eigen value for the all
一个矢量，所以我做一做，你知道这
one's vector so I do a do you know this
MATLAB命令逐个组件
MATLAB command component by component
乘法这是一个重要的
multiplication this is it's an important
一个人的名字也是
one there's a guy's name is also
与之相关联，所以这是一个
associated with that so so that's a
矢量，这是一个矢量，什么来了
vector that's a vector and what comes
如果我有一个向量，那就完成了那个操作
out of that operation if I have a vector
有三个组件所以n在这里是三个
with three components so n is three here
我确实指出明星或点星我不是
and I do point star or dot star I'm not
确定人们通常所说的组件
sure what people usually say component
通过组件三组分向量
by component a three component vector
我得到一个三分量矢量的时间
times a three component vector I get a
三个分量矢量就这样
three component vector just like that
是的，所以这就是卷积
yeah yeah so this is the convolution
规则是卷积和
rule that's the convolution and the
证明就是当特征时的事实
proof is the fact that eigen that when
矩阵通勤的本征值
matrices commute the eigen values of the
产品或只是这些特征值时间
product or just these eigen values times
这些特征值因为它们具有
these eigen values because they have the
同样的本征特征向量总是如此
same eigen the eigen vectors are always
对于所有这些循环都是如此
the same here for all these circulant so
我可以使用卷积规则
there's the convolution rule that I can
传达然后变换或我可以变换
convey then transform or I can transform
分开然后再乘以
separately and then multiply so just
或许更好地写出卷积
maybe better write that the convolution
我们称之为C规则卷积
let's call it the C rule convolve then
由F变换或单独变换
transform by F or transform separately
用F然后再乘以点
by F and then then multiply point wise
你知道元素是啊
you know element by element yeah
一些奖金好耶这样组件
component by some bonus okay yeah so
这是卷积规则，为什么是
that's the convolution rule and why is
它有点为什么如此重要
it sort of why is it so important
因为F乘以变换
because transforming by F multiplying by
傅里叶矩阵非常快
the Fourier matrix is extremely fast by
在FFT所以所以它是有用的，因为的
the FFT so so it's useful because of the
FFT快速傅立叶变换到
FFT the fast Fourier transform to
乘以yep或转换为哪一个
multiply yep or to transform whichever
乘以F变换
multiplied by F transform
所以它就是存在的存在
so it's it's the it's the exist presence
使它成为现实的FFT给了我们一个
of the FFT that makes this it gives us a
真的两种不同的方式来做到这一点
really two different ways to do it
其实这是更快的方式，所以我们
in fact which is the faster way so we
可以通过这种方式产生相同的结果
can produce the same result this way or
这样，如果我不计算成本
this way and if I don't count the cost
如果乘以F的成本是
of if the cost of multiplying by F is
低，因为我有FFT
low because I have the FFT which would
你做
you do
你会这样做让我放手吧
which would you do so let's let me just
在我们回答之前大声思考
think aloud before we answer that
问题，然后我们是好的，如果
question and then we're we're good so if
我所以我的向量有n个组件，所以一个
I so my vectors have n components so one
我能做的就是如何做卷积
way I can do is to do convolution how
如果我拿走一个，有多少步骤
many how many steps is that if I take a
矢量与n个组件，我卷积
vector with n components and I convolve
用n个组件的向量有多少
with a vector with n components how many
我必须做很少的乘法
little multiplications do I have to do
因为每个C都是正确的
and square right because each of the C's
必须将每个DS乘以这样
has to multiply each of the DS so that
拿N平方和傅立叶很便宜
takes N squared and Fourier is cheap
它的N日志N日志基数为二，因此
it's n log n log to base 2 so the
左手边实际上是立方体
left-hand side is effectively in cubed
这个如何
what about this one
这两个人做多少了多少
how many up how many to do these two
男人找傅立叶变换
guys to find the Fourier transform to
乘以矩阵Fok即可
multiply by the matrix F ok those are
再快，这只是我有两个
fast again that's just I've got two
乘以F得到2nlogN.
multiplications by F so that's 2 n log N
什么是这样做的成本
and what's the cost of this
我有一个带有n个成分点的矢量
I have a vector with n components dot
明星矢量另一种向量与n
star vector another vector with n
组件有多少
components how many little
我必须做的乘法
multiplications do I have to do for a
Hadamard产品或一个或一个组件
Hadamard product or a or a component by
组件产品n只在+中是的我
component product n only in + in yeah I
也许我应该做那个+
should maybe I should have made that +
是啊是啊我有我只好我知道我有
yeah yeah I had I had to I know I had
一个nlogn加上它取M平方
one n log n plus it took M squared to
找到那个向量，然后nlogn
find that vector and then n log n so
它的有效ñ平方但这一次
it's effectively N squared but this one
我在那里做Nlogn两次然后我
where I do the N log n twice and then I
只有它才会让我更多，所以这是
only it only takes me in more so this is
快速的方式，如果你想
the fast way so if you wanted to
乘以两个非常大的长整数
multiply two really big long integers as
你想要在密码学中做什么
you would want to do in in cryptography
如果你有两个长整数说
if you had two long integers say of
长度125126128128组件
length 125 126 128 128 components to
乘那些你会过得更好
multiply those you would be better off
分别进行循环变换
to separately take the cyclic transform
这些百人中的每一个
of each of those hundred and
二十八个家伙，这样做
twenty-eight guys and do it this way
拿这个转变来做
take this take the transforms do the
逐个组件产品然后
component by component product and then
变换回拿到呀没错如此
transform back to get that yeah yep so
这是卷积规则的原因
it's the convolution rule is what makes
那个没关系，所以哦，还有一个
that go okay so that's oh one more
以为我想这一切
thought I guess about all this
卷积的东西假设我们在2d我们
convolution stuff suppose we're in 2d we
不得不考虑什么是什么
have to think what's what is a
二维卷积是什么
two-dimensional convolution what does
这成了
this become
在两个方面假设我们有
in two dimensions suppose we have
功能所以现在我将成为
functions so now I'm to be functions of
x和y周期性或非周期性但是
x and y periodic or not periodic but
什么是卷积是什么？
what will we what's a convolution what's
我们要做的操作有两个
the operation we have to do in two
尺寸很好，它是一个双重积分
dimensions well it's a double integral
当然T和你我们会做T和T.
of course T and u we would do F of T and
u乘以X的G减去TDu和
u times G of X minus t y- u d TD u and
这将产生一个功能，所以我
that would produce a function so i'm
将x和y的函数与...进行卷积
convolving a function of x and y with
X的另一个功能，我也是
another function of X and again I'm
寻找这这这是
looking for the this this this is the
关键看为x轴牛逼Y-ü认为这是
key to watch for x- t y- u that that's
卷积积分的信号
the signal of a convolution integral
是的，这就是我们所拥有的
yeah so that that's what we would have
在2d的将军中，你可能会这么多
in 2d in generals do you so much may be
我现在最后的想法是搬到
mine now my final thought is to move to
考虑二维矩阵和
think about two dimensional matrices and
及其产品等，这是
and their products and so on and this is
为什么你需要它们，因为你就是这样
why you need them because you're you if
如果你有二维，那就是你
you're if you have two dimensional
信号然后组件适合a
signals then the components fit into a
矩阵，我们只需要操作
matrix and we just have to operate in
这两个方面都是如此关键
both dimensions so so the the key
他们在2d的关键操作是在MATLAB中
their key operation in 2d is in MATLAB
您需要知道的MATLAB命令
the MATLAB command that you need to know
如果你知道你在做什么，就得到
to get if you know what you're doing in
1d你想在2d做到
1d and you want to do it in 2d the
MATLAB命令是cron所以我们想象
MATLAB command is cron so so we imagine
我们有一维矩阵a和B.
we have one dimensional matrices a and B
所以那些是1d而我们想要的
and so those are in 1d and we want to
为他们生产自然
produce the natural to them
二维矩阵所以这些将是
two-dimensional matrix so these will be
由M和我们想要那种自然
n by M and we want the sort of natural
产品让我称之为k为cron
product let me call it k for cron which
我想要的N平方N平方
will be N squared by N squared I want to
创建一个连接到的二维矩阵
create a 2d matrix with connected to an
图像这n个所以每个方向
image that's n in each direction so it
有它有N个平方像素，这是
has it has N squared pixels this is
这些是1d信号，K是2d信号
these are 1d signals and K is a 2d one
而这个洞穴就在那里
and this cave would be there this is the
知道给予的操作
operation to know given given to one
维数n乘n矩阵cron
dimensional N by n matrices cron
产生一个N平方N平方
produces a to an N squared by N squared
矩阵
matrix
它病了，这是一个了解的操作
it's sick it's a operation to know so
如果你知道什么，我会把它写进来
I'll just write it in if you know what
cron是，你知道你知道什么
cron is and you know what you know it
在我写之前，我想要的是什么
before I write it so what so I want to
产生一个由N组成的矩阵
produce a big matrix n squared by N
平方
squared
以某种方式适当地增加这些
somehow appropriately multiplying these
两个家伙和适当的方式做
two guys and the appropriate way to do
取一个1并乘以B
it is to take a 1 1 and multiplied by B
所以有什么我有什么大小有我
so there what do I have what size have I
得到他们已经只是在那一个
got they're already just in that one
角落n由右边它是多次
corner n by n right it's a number times
N乘n矩阵然后是1/2的B
an N by n matrix then a 1/2 times B
这是另一个n乘n矩阵，最高可达1n
that's another n by n matrix up to a 1 n
倍B所以我现在抱歉Kappa所以我
times B so I have now sorry Kappa so I
每个都有一个插入式矩阵
have tap-in matrices in a row each of
那些矩阵是n，所以我的那一行
those matrices is n by n so my that row
长度N平方，当然是
has length N squared and of course the
下一行是我已经允许自己
next row is I've I've allowed myself to
数字从1到N但很常见
number from 1 to N but very often that
编号应为0到n减1和
numbering should be 0 to n minus 1 and
最后在这里下降到1和1
finally going down here down to a and 1
B所以N是N的平方
B so so that's the N squared by N
平方矩阵，你需要
squared matrix that you would need to
知道例如，如果你想要做一个
know for example if you wanted to do a
你转变的二维转移
two dimensional transfer you transform
它会是的，所以两个会是什么
it would be yeah so what would a two
每个维度傅里叶变换
dimensional Fourier transform per do
这个矩阵是什么矩阵你
what what matrix is this the matrix you
会用一个2D我没有那种
would use for for a 2d I haven't sort of
在2d傅立叶上正确开始
got started properly on 2d Fourier
变换所以它会是F次FF
transform so would it be F times F F
请让我写下来
cronic so let me write down the full
这个家伙chroniker的名字是这样的
name of this guy chroniker so it's
它就是Kronecker产品
called the Kronecker product it's just
知道这是正确的事情
it's just the right thing to know in
从一个维度移动到两个维度
moving from one dimension to two
尺寸例如让我
dimensions for example let me
我有一块板，是的，是的，所以在这里
I got one board left yeah yeah so here's
标准矩阵称它为二和
a standard matrix call it a twos and
减去这就是那个合唱
minus ones so that that's that chorus
这对应于二阶导数
that corresponds to a second derivative
或实际减去二阶导数
or actually minus the second derivative
现在假设我有另一个配偶
now suppose I have a mate another the
对应于第二个的相同矩阵
same matrix corresponding to second
衍生物在Y方向上相同而且
derivatives in the Y direction same and
我真正想要做的就是我想要的
what I really want to do is both I want
有一个对应的矩阵K.
to have a matrix K that corresponds to
减去X方向的第二个
minus the second in the X Direction
减去第二个和Y所以这是
minus the second and the Y so this is
拉普拉斯拉普拉西亚到处都是
the Laplace laplacian which is all over
a中微分方程的位置
the place in differential equations at a
我想做的典型点-其中之一
typical point I want to do - one of
这两个-其中一个
these two of these - one of those in the
X方向，我想补充一点
X direction and I want to add to that
减去一个现在也变成了四个
minus one now that too becomes a four
在Y方向减去一个，所以我
and minus one in the Y direction so I'm
寻找两个伙伴的两个人
looking for the two by two mate
二维矩阵
the the two dimensional matrix that
采取那种五点计划
takes that does that five-point scheme
每个点的五个权重需要四个
five weights for each point takes four
在对角线和减去一个上
of the on the diagonal and minus one on
四个邻居和操作
the four neighbors and the operation
这样做会是你会的
that would do that would be you would
使用cron它不会是B的cron
use cron it wouldn't be cron of a B that
只是B的B不是我的意思
would just K of a B is not what I what I
是B的cron不是我想要的
was a cron of a B is not what I want
是的，那会做一个，然后是
yeah that would do one and then the
另一个然后那可能
other one and then that would probably
产生九个非零我想要的东西
produce nine non-zeros I want something
在这里添加所以我想要一个cron
that adds here so I I want cron of a
时间是给我的身份
time's the identity that gives me the
这部分的二维事物
the two dimensional thing for this part
然后我会加上我的cron
and then I'll add on cron of I be for
衍生物的垂直导数
the vertical derivative the derivatives
在Y方向，所以就是这样
in the Y direction so that would be so
这被称为chroniker，这是一个
that's called a chroniker some this is a
这是一个另一个是chroniker
this is a the other was a chroniker
产品，这将是一个慢性病
product so that would be a chronica
产品这将是另一个Kronecker
product this would be another Kronecker
产品和总称为
product and that total is called the
chroniker好吧我想要得到
chroniker some okay I wanted just to get
这些符号是因为真的
that those notations out because really
你知道傅立叶改造我说的是
you know Fourier transforming I said is
所有这样的中央运作
such a central operation in in in all of
应用混乱，尤其是信号
Applied mess and especially in signal
处理好，所以今天我很好
processing okay so I'm good for today
让我们看看到目前为止我有一名志愿者
let's see I've got one volunteer so far
我可以谈谈一个项目
for to talk about a project can I
鼓励任何人发送电子邮件
encourage an email from anybody it
难道你不必成为超级巨星
doesn't you don't have to be a superstar
它只是愿意这样做告诉我们
it's just willing to to do it tell us
关于你学到的东西得到的东西
something about what you've learned get
从观众的评论，你知道
comments from the audience and you know
我十分十五分钟
ten ten or fifteen minutes is all I'm
想着它，好吧，我会告诉你的
thinking about it yeah okay I'll let you
如果你愿意的话，给我发一封电子邮件
send me an email if you're if you'd like
告诉我们，并得到一些反馈确定
to tell us that and get some feedback ok
好，所以我星期三见
good so I'll see you Wednesday
谢谢
Thanks